A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Governance and Public Policy (GPP), Office Files of Marcia Smith FA544
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Governance and Public Policy (GPP), Office Files of Marcia Smith
1993-1995
Rockefeller Archive Center
Smith, Marcia
Ford Foundation
FA544
2.62 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
Primarily documents the Women's Program Forum.
Biographical / Historical
Marcia Smith is a documentary filmmaker and former foundation executive who worked for several years at the Ford Foundation. She joined the Foundation as a Program Officer in the Rights and Social Justice Program (RSJ) and then moved to the Governance and Public Policy Program (GPP). Following a change in the Foundation's program structure, she became a Program Officer in the Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society unit (GCS). She was later appointed Deputy Director of the GCS unit.
Smith is the Co-Founder and President of Firelight Media, a non-profit filmmaking company which produces documentary films and provides support to emerging filmmakers of color. She has written films produced by Firelight Media like "The Murder of Emmett Till" and "Freedom Riders". From 2008 to 2011, she served as Senior Vice President of Atlantic Philanthropies.
Smith earned a B.S. in media production from Emerson College and a M.S. from Hunter College.
Arrangement
As received.
- Marcia Smith -- Africa Region, 1995 (Box 1)
- Marcia Smith -- Asia Region, 1995 (Box 1)
- Marcia Smith -- Field Offices, 1995 (Box 1)
- Beijing Followup, 1994 (Box 1)
- Invitation Letters, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
- NGO Registration, 1995 March 13-14 (Box 1)
- 4th World Conference on Women, Beijing China, 1995 August 29-September 16 (Box 1)
- Post Election Roundtable, 1995 January 30 (Box 1)
- Post Election Roundtable, 1995 January 31 (Box 1)
- Background Material for Post Election Meetings, 1995 January 30-31 (Box 1)
- WPF (Women's Program Forum) Women's Conference -- Conference Documents, 1995 (Box 1)
- WPF Women's Conference -- Media, 1995 May (Box 1)
- WPF World Conference on Women -- Planning Group / Forum Member List, 1995 (Box 1)
- Women's Program Forum (WPF) -- Fourth World Conference on Women -- 1995 Donors, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
- WPF -- Fourth World Conference on Women -- Beijing Donor Meeting, 1995 (Box 2)
- WPF -- Fourth World Conference on Women -- Media and Preparations, 1993-1995 (Box 2)
- WPF -- Fourth World Conference on Women -- NGO's -- Conference Planning, 1993-1995 (Box 2)
- WPF -- Fourth World Conference on Women -- Planning Group, 1993-1995 (Box 2)
- WPF -- Fourth World Conference on Women -- 1995 Platform, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
- WPF -- Fourth World Conference on Women -- Proposals, 1993-1995 (Box 2)
- WPF -- Fourth World Conference on Women -- Strategy and Grantmaking Memo, 1994 November (Box 2)
- WPF -- Fourth World Conference on Women -- U.S. Official Preparations, 1994 (Box 2)
- WPF -- Fourth World Conference on Women -- "Women in Decision Making" Advisory Group, 1993-1994 (Box 2)
- WPF -- Consultancy, 1995 (Box 2)
- WPF -- NGO Consultation (UN Headquarters, March 13-14, 1995), 1995 March (Box 2)
- WPF -- NGO Forum on Women, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
- WPF -- 1995 NGO Forum, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
- WPF Luncheon -- Re: Prepcom and NGO Consultation -- Attendance List, 1995 March 15 (Box 2)
- WPF Working Group -- Foundation Concept Paper -- "Beijing and Beyond", 1995 (Box 2)